DANH PHAN

Data Scientist

danh.phan.mq@gmail.com

+61 416 978 987

https://danhphan.net

in /danhpt

/danhpt 7 /danhphan



Full working rights in Australia

Hi, my name is Danh Phan. Applying Machine learning and Big data analysis to derive actionable insights is my passion. I am a Data Scientist at the Pacific service team, Johnson Controls Australia. I am also a researcher working on various machine learning methods for intelligent transport systems at Monash University. I have contributed to open-source projects like PyMC, a popular probabilistic programming framework in Python.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Apr 2022 - Present **Data Analyst** Oct 2021 - Mar 2022 Melbourne, Australia Johnson Controls Australia

Develop Dynamic Pricing Models; Margin and Conversion rate optimisation; Customer churn modelling; Perform data analysis and build various KPIs and BI dashboards; Improve data quality, data governance and data security; Build and deploy End to End ML applications on Microsoft Azure.

Open-source software developer

Jan 2022 - Present PyMC Github

PyMC contributor Develop Python functions, classes, and docker images for open-source projects that focus on Bayesian Modelling and Probabilistic Machine Learning, including packages like PyMC, Aesara, and PyMC-Examples.

Data Science Associate Instructor

Jul 2021 - Present

Data Fluency, Monash University

Melbourne, Australia

Prepare technical materials; Teach hands-on workshops on machine learning, data analysis with Python, and data visualisation (Power BI) for professional staff and researchers at Monash University; Lead a group of four instructors.

Data Analyst Intern

Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

Data Department, Domain Group

Sydney, Australia

Developed customer clustering models for marketing and sales teams; Performed data analysis using SQL, ETL, Python; Building various dashboards with Tableau.

Casual Teaching Academic

Feb 2018 - Nov 2018

Computing Department, Macquarie University

Sydney, Australia

Tutored and consulted students on System Integration, and IT Systems & Projects.

IT Specialist Sep 2013 - Oct 2016

Dept. of Information and Communications of NgheAn

Vietnam

Developed and maintained web applications and SQL databases.

RECENT PROJECTS (please check other projects at https://github.com/danhphan)

[1] Aussie Social Sentiment Analysis (https://aussie-sentiments.herokuapp.com)

This project collects data from Twitter's APIs and build sentiment analysis models.

[2] Advanced Python features (https://danhphan.github.io/explore)

This project explores and examines various python packages and features.

[3] Melbournian Daily Activities (https://melbourn-city.herokuapp.com)

This project visualises the daily activities of Melbournians in different areas.

EDUCATION

PhD Candidate on Intelligent Transport Systems

Feb 2020 - Present *Melbourne*, *Australia*

Institute of Transport Studies, Monash University

Supervisors: Prof. Hai Vu, Prof. Graham Currie

Topic: Machine learning for transport systems; Activity-based Agent-based models.

Master of Information Technology

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018

Sydney, Australia

Macquarie University
Final internship: Data Analyst at Domain Group

Core units: Machine Learning, Data Mining, Information Systems, Security Management

GPA 6.733/7 (4.0/4.0); Top one postgraduate student; Academic Excellence Award

Bachelor of Information Technology

Aug 2005 - Jul 2010

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Hanoi, Vietnam

Core units: Probability and Statistics, Algebra and Analytic, Numerical methods, Discrete Mathematics, Artificial Intelligence, Data structures and algorithms, Software Engineering.

GPA 8.3/10; High Distinction; Faculty rank 1/39

PUBLICATIONS

[1] Danh T. Phan, Hai L. Vu, Graham Currie. **AttentionChoice: Discrete choice modelling supported by a deep learning attention mechanism**. *The Transportation Research Board (TRB)*, 2022, under review.

[2] Danh T. Phan, Hai L. Vu, Eric J. Miller. A New Approach to Improve Destination Choice by Ranking Personal Preferences. *Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies*, 2022. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0968090X22002406

[3] Danh T. Phan, Hai L. Vu. Activity pattern generation incorporating deep learning for transport demand models. 2021. https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.02278

[4] Danh T. Phan. Smart Mobility Improvement: Classifying Commuter Satisfaction in Sydney, Australia. In Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Machine Learning and Soft Computing (ICMLSC 2019). https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3311021

[5] Danh T. Phan. Australia Housing Price Prediction using Machine Learning Algorithms: The Case of Melbourne City, Australia. *The 2018 International Conference on Machine Learning and Data Engineering*. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8614000

CORE SKILLS

Technical: Python, R, Java, C++, C#, .NET, SQL, ETL, Data Factory, Data Warehouse

Data analysis: Numpy, Jax, Pandas, GeoPandas, Scipy, NLTK, Dask, PySpark

Machine learning: Scikit-learn, Pytorch, Spacy, Statsmodels, PyMC, Aesara

Other tools: MySql, Sql Server, Docker, CI/CD, DevOps, Tableau, Power BI

Environments: Linux, AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud, Salesforce, ServiceMax

CERTIFICATES

•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate - Microsoft	Sep 2022
•	Bayesian Data Analysis in Python - DataCamp	Nov 2021
•	Deep Learning Specialization - Coursera	Sep 2021
•	Scalable Machine Learning with Apache Spark - Databricks	Jul 2021
•	Discrete Choice Analysis: Predicting Market Demand - MIT	Jun 2021